so the ad is here producing a value of
r1 that is not a problem because the
previous instruction is just producing
r2 so the ad can write its result when
it's time and when it executed in cycle
three so it's gonna write in cycle five
now let's look at this multiplication
instruction over here remember we can
execute any number of instructions in
the in the same cycle the reason why we
had to delay the ad is because it
actually has this dependence from r2 to
r2 the multiplication is using only r3
and producing r3 using r3 has no problem
because neither the man nor the other
producing r3 so this multiplication can
actually execute in cycle two and then
there is no problem with r3 here because
there is only r1 and r2 written by the
previous instructions so this
multiplication can actually write r3 in
cycle four because it's like two three
four now let's look at this ad here it
uses r1 and r3 the r1 is supposed to be
using is produced by this ad which
executes is cycle three the r3 is
produced in cycle two by the
multiplication so this instruction
actually has to wait for cycle four
because of this then it's going to be
cycle five when it's in the mem stage
and it's able to write its result in
cycle six it's going to overwrite the
results from the ad here but because the
ad is writing in cycle five it's okay if
you write in cycle six so everything is
fine here we can write in cycle six now
let's look at the multiplication here
it's using our four none of the other
instructions are producing r4 so it can
also execute in the second cycle it
produces r4 none of the previous
instructions are writing is so we have
don't have to wait for anything so we
can actually write our r4 in cycle four
as well just like this small here and
then finally let's look at this ad here
it's using r1 from here it's using r4
from here so our execution has to be in
the cycle that follows the larger of
these two the larger is the cycle four
so we have to begin our execution in
cycle five here at the end of cycle five
day we will have the result than the
moment we can write the result in cycle
seven but we have to check
is somebody else gonna overwrite it
later and that's not going to happen
because if we right here in cycle seven
we are safe this is the latest
instruction it should do the right of
the r1 at the latest time among all the
other instructions and if you look at
the previous instructions have written
the results in cycle five and cycle six
so it's okay if we here write it in
cycle seven so this is the solution to
the quiz